Guide to the Freshman Life Reference Collection, 1946-ongoing
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Freshman Life Reference collection 1946-ongoing
University Archives, Duke University
Duke University. University Archives
0.5 Linear Feet 200 Items
The Freshman Life Reference Collection contains files of orientation guides, brochures, flyers, newspaper clippings, memoranda and other materials that document the experience of first-year students. This collection was compiled from a variety of sources by the University Archives for use in reference and research.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Freshman Life Reference Collection was compiled by University Archives staff from a variety of sources.
Collection Overview
The Freshman Life Reference Collection contains orientation handbooks, brochures, flyers, newspaper clippings, memoranda and other materials concerning the first-year student experience. Major subjects include orientation and orientation planning, summer reading lists, and Duke University traditions. Materials include a letter, 1965, to incoming students from Sam Southern, Class of 1966, advertising the Official Duke blazer; a traditions handout, ca. 1956, ascribed to Ken Albrecht and Don Duffy, and a copy of volume 1, no. 1 of The Imp, a freshman newsletter for the Class of 1954. There are cataloged sets of the orientation handbooks.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Albrecht, Kenneth.
College freshmen -- North Carolina -- Durham.
College student orientation -- North Carolina -- Durham.
Duffy, Donald.
Duke University -- Insignia.
Duke University. Traditions Board.
Southern, Samuel.
Universities and colleges -- traditions.
Related Material
Design For a Duchess / Duke University. Women's Student Government Association. Social Standards Committee, 1954-1963 (span).
University Archives, Duke University.
The Duke freshman record, Class of .. / Academic Dean of Freshmen and the Associated Students of Duke University, [1972- ] [Freshman class directory].
University Archives, Duke University.
The Duke gentleman / Young Men's Christian Association, Duke University, [1964?]-[1968].
University Archives, Duke University.
The Duke handbook / Young Men's Christian Association, Duke University [1930?]-[1948?].
University Archives, Duke University.
Duke University history and traditions / Duke University. Men's Student Government Association. Traditions Board, 1964.
University Archives, Duke University.
: Handbook of Duke University / Y.M. and Y.W.C.A.'s, [1926?]-[1930?].
University Archives, Duke University.
It's not in the Handbook / Duke University. Women's Student Government Association. Social Standards Committee, 1936-1969 (span).
University Archives, Duke University.
The University experience / YMCA, Duke University, [1969]-[1977].
University Archives, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 1 Box
  - Blue Book, Orientation manual for the Class of 2011 (Box 1)
  - Class of ___
  - Flyers, 1971, 1975
  - Freshman arrival, clippings, 1975-1978
  - Freshman life, clippings, 1975-2001
  - Freshman reading lists, 1965-1969
  - Freshman Seminars and Faculty Lecture Series, 1987, 1990, 1995
  - Freshmen Traditions: Dinks
  - Handbooks
  - Academic Guide for Freshmen, 1960, 1971-1974, 1976
  - Duke Is Now Your University, 1949, 1951, 1953
  - Freshman Week Program / Orientation week / Freshman Week, Trinity College and School of Engineering, 1935-1971 [incomplete]
  - Freshman Week / Orientation Week, The Woman's College, 1951-1972 [incomplete]
  - Freshman Week / New Student Orientation, Trinity College of Arts and Sciences and the School of Engineering, 1972-1999 [incomplete]
  - Duke Insider (class of 2010), 2008/09
  - The Imp, 1950 [Class of 1954 newsletter]
  - Official Duke blazer, 1965
  - Orientation, 1975-1981
  - Orientation planning, 1946-1950, 1954, 1970-1971
  - Program for accepted Students: Perspectives on Duke, 1993
  - Traditions Board [ca. 1956]